- Potts?
- Yeah.
Bill Potts?
You wanted to see me?
You're not a student of this university?
No. I work in the canteen.
- Yeah. but you come to my lectures.
- No. I don't.
I never do that.
I've seen you.
Love your lectures.
they're totally awesome.
Why did you come to my lectures.
when you're not a student?
Okay. so my first day here.
in the canteen. I was on chips.
There was this girl.
student. beautiful.
like a model.
only with talking and thinking.
She looked at you and you perved.
Every time. Automatic like physics.
eye contact. perversion.
So. I gave her extra chips.
Every time. extra chips.
Like a reward. for perversion.
Every day. got myself on chips.
rewarded her.
Then finally. finally. she looked at me.
like she didn't notice that I actually
noticed all the extra chips.
Do you know what I realised?
She was fat.
I had fatted her.
That's life. isn't it?
Beauty or chips? I like chips.
So does she. so... That's okay.
And how does that in any way explain
why you keep coming to my lectures?
Yeah. it doesn't really. does it?
I was hoping something would develop.
What's that?
A police telephone box?
- Yeah.
- Did you build it from a kit?
- No. it came like that.
- Then. how did you get it in here?
The door is too small.
and so are the windows.
I had the window and a part of the wall
taken out. and it was lifted in.
- Oh. with a crane?
- Yeah.
With a crane.
It's heavier than it looks.
Why do you keep coming to my lectures?
Because I like them.
Everybody likes them. they're amazing.
- Why me?
- Why you. what?
Well. plenty of people come
to your lectures
that aren't supposed to.
why pick on me?
Well. I noticed you.
Yeah. but why?
Well. most people. when they don't
understand something. they frown.
You...
Smile.
Tell you what I don't understand.
You've been lecturing here a long time.
about 50 years. some people say.
- My B-Line in the office says over 70.
- Yeah.
and you're thinking.
"Well. he doesn't look old enough."
No. I'm wondering what you're
supposed to be lecturing on?
It's like the university let
you do whatever you like.
One time. you were going to give
a lecture on quantum physics.
you talked about poetry.
Poetry. physics. same thing.
How is it the same?
Because of the rhymes.
what are you doing at this university?
I always wanted to come here.
Yeah. to serve chips?
So anyway. am I nearly done?
Do you wanna be?
See ya.
You ever get less
than a first and it's over.
- You what?
- A first.
every time.
or I stop immediately.
Stop what?
Being your personal tutor.
But I'm not a student.
I'm not a part of the university.
I never even applied.
We'll sort all of that out later.
You kinda have to sort that out earlier.
Leave it with me.
I'm assuming that it's a "yes"?
Yes.
I'll see you at 6:00 p.m. every weekday.
I don't care who is dying.
never. ever be late.
I'm very particular about time.
Oh...
People just call you "The Doctor".
What do I call you?
The Doctor.
But Doctor's not a name.
I can't just call you Doctor.
Doctor what?
Time. Time doesn't pass.
The passage of time is an illusion.
and life is the magician.
because life only lets you
see one day at a time.
You remember being alive yesterday.
you hope you're going
to be alive tomorrow.
So. it feels like you're travelling
one to the other.
but nobody is moving anywhere.
Movies don't really move.
They're just pictures.
lots and lots of pictures.
All of them still. none of them moving.
just frozen moments.
If you experience those
pictures one after the other...
then everything comes alive.
Am I on time?
That's a very big question.
You know. you're my foster mum.
he's like my foster tutor.
Am I gonna have to break
every bone in his body?
It's not like that.
You need to keep your eye on men.
Men aren't where
I keep my eye actually.
Imagine if time all happened at once...
every moment of your life
laid out around you
like a city.
Streets full of buildings. made of days.
The day you were born. the day you die.
the day you fall in love.
the day that love ends. A whole city.
built from triumph and heartbreak
and boredom and laughter
and cutting your toenails.
it's the best place you'll ever be.
Time is a structure.
relative to ourselves.
I'll get him in.
Time is the space
made by our lives.
where we stand together forever.
Time
and relative dimension
in
Space.
It means life.
- Chips. yeah?
- Please.
Huh. oh!
So. you're tutoring her and...
Mmm-hmm. yes I am.
- Why?
- Why not?
You're not supposed
to be get involved.
What are you teaching her anyway?
Everything.
How can you teach
anyone everything?
- Because everything rhymes.
- Oh.
- Rotate it.
- Ah.
The door upstairs.
how did you set the security?
Friends only.
So. turn it and then it'll...
I'm turning it. help me.
- You okay?
- Yeah. I'm fine.
Sorry. can I ask?
What's that in your eye?
It's just a defect in the iris.
- Looks like a star.
- Well. it's a defect.
At least.
it's a defect that looks like a star.
I'm getting it fixed.
Okay-
Sorry. none of my business.
but are you freaking out
about something?
Please. you can say no.
Would you come with me.
can I show you something?
God. yes!
I love this place. don't you?
- I hate it.
- Why?
I don't know. I just do.
Everywhere I go. I just wanna leave.
Can I come. too?
Maybe.
There's a puddle over there.
It hasn't rained for a week.
Yeah. but... Well. you know.
half the students here are blokes.
Go and look in it.
- You want me to look in a puddle?
- Please.
Okay. I'm lookin'.
- What am I lookin' at?
- Your reflection.
Yep. there it is.
Did you see
what's wrong with it?
My name's Bill. by the way.
I'm Heather.
Can you see what's wrong?
Nothing. just looks like me.
Oh! What is that?
That's me. that's my face but
it's wrong.
Hey!
Sorry. some other time.
Promise?
Pilot is located.
Link is established.
It's a rug.
Haven't got you anything.
It's okay.
It was cheap.
Going anywhere for Christmas?
I never go anywhere.
That's not true.
You go places. I can tell.
My mum always said. "With some people".
"you can smell the wind
in their clothes".
Hmm?
She sounds...
Nice.
She died when I was a baby.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
If she died when you were a baby.
when did she say that?
In my head.
Yeah. I'm supposed to look like her.
but I don't really know.
There's hardly any photographs.
She hated having her picture taken.
But if someone's gone.
do pictures really help?
I thought you'd enjoy choosing
something for yourself.
as you're always passing judgements.
I hope you didn't spend
too much on this.
Nah. this should cover it.
What's that?
Oh. I found that in the back of a
cupboard. with all your old stuff.
Just photographs. of your mum.
I didn't know we had 'em.
Happy new term!
With you in a moment.
You said you needed
a crane to lift your box.
Sorry. what did you say?
Hey!
Still making eyes at a puddle?
Did you ever work out what
was wrong with your reflection?
Nah.
Come around. I'll show you.
Promise you won't go.
Promise.
Okay-
Yeah. no worries.
Pilot confirmed.
pilot engaged.
What's wrong?
She said it was a defect.
But. what kind of a defect
puts a star in your eye?
But that doesn't even matter
because she was right.
There was something wrong when
you looked in the puddle.
That was definitely my face.
I see my face all the time.
I never liked it.
it's all over the place.
It's always doing expressions when
I'm trying to be enigmatic
I know my face.
And there was something wrong
with my face in the puddle.
What could be wrong with your own face?
Doctor!
- Why did you run like that?
- Like what?
Like a penguin. with his arse on fire.
Ergonomics.
That's my face. yeah?
I see you're a bit flexible
on the subject.
Oh. you've no idea.
Maybe it's got to do with
that thing in her eye.
- How?
- Maybe she's like.
affected by something.
- By what?
- I don't know.
Look. I know you know lots of stuff
about. well. basically everything.
but do you know any sci-fi?
- Go on.
- Well.
what if she's possessed?
Something like that?
Possessed by what?
I don't know.
Saw this thing on Netflix.
lizards in people's brains.
Right. so you meet a girl
with a discoloured iris.
and your first thought is.
she might have a lizard in her brain?
I can see I'm gonna have to up my game.
Oh!
- What?
- Oh!
- What is it. what?
- Oh. I get it.
I see it.
It was easy for you friend.
because of her eye.
What? Because it gives her
special powers?
No!
Because her face
isn't symmetrical. look.
Look into the puddle.
Your face looks wrong.
because it looks right.
What's the one thing you never see when
you're looking in a reflection?
Your face. You never see
your face the right way around.
Right. look for a freckle
or a funny tooth.
- something that's not...
- My badge!
See. your friend saw it straight
away because of her eye.
But that means we're like. a reflection.
It's not
reflecting you.
it's mimicking you.
There's something in the water.
pretending to be you.
Of course.
it isn't water.
Now. what are these?
Let's have a look.
What are they?
Scorch marks.
Interesting.
Right. you!
Let's get you on the bus.
The what? The bus?
Tutorial's over. take the night off.
It's all cancelled.
Go and be a proper student.
Text. snogging. a vegan wrap.
But what about the puddle?
Oh. it's just some freak optical effect.
I'm bored already.
Passenger selected.
pursuit engaged.
Hey. I'll make you a cuppa for the bath.
Hey.
Sorry. I'm not there. love.
But I think we both know.
it's time I treated myself.
Are you with Neville?
Why would! be back with Neville.
after last time?
Why do you think I'm such an idiot?
Well. you're calling from his phone.
Is there someone staying here
in the flat?
Of course not. No.
What are you talking about?
Nothing. never mind.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hello?
Is someone in there?
Is that Barry?
Because she's with Neville.
and it's not my fault.
Sorry. I need to know who's in there.
I'm coming in.
Do you hear me?
Make yourself decent.
If that's Barry.
let's not make this worse.
just say it's you.
Hey!
Hello.
You scared me.
You're dead.
Hello. Bill.
Oh...
What's that?
I'll tell you what it isn't.
It isn't a freak optical effect.
And it's following me.
No. No. What are you doing?
I'll tell you what.
let's just pop into my box.
Your box? What good
is getting in your box going to do?
What an extraordinarily long
and involved answer this is going to be.
How do we stop her getting in?
- We're trapped in here.
- Nothing gets through these doors.
But they're made of wood.
They've got windows!
Look. This is all mad. I know. but...
That's the girl I told you about.
Heather.
Only. I don't think it's really her.
I know this is hard to believe. I know
you're not exactly a sci-fi person...
Time and Relative Dimension in Space.
TARDIS for short.
You're safe in here.
You're safe in here
and you always will be.
Any questions?
Is this a knock through?
Well. in a way. yes.
Look at this place.
- It's like a...
- Spaceship.
- Kitchen.
- A what?
A really posh kitchen. All metal.
What happened to the doors though?
Did you run out of money?
What you are standing in
is a technological marvel.
It is science beyond magic.
This is the gateway
to everything that ever was.
Whatever can be.
Can I use the toilet?
- Pardon?
- I've had a fright. I need the toilet.
It's down there. First right. second
left. past the macaroon dispenser.
- Thanks.
- Oh! Human.
Human alert.
Do you want me to repel her?
She's just passing through.
She wants to use the toilet.
Oh. I'd give it a minute if I were you.
Oh! What's that?
We have a encroacher on campus.
Extra-terrestrial. We're under attack.
Let's move.
Oh. my God!
- This isn't just a room. is it?
- No. it's not just a room.
This is a lift!
Well. come on.
No interference here as far
as I can see. Vault secure.
So. your box can move?
It can go anywhere it likes.
Mmm. Good. innit?
Anywhere at all in the whole university?
Is it my imagination or is this
taking longer than normal?
Hang on.
The room's still inside the box.
- This isn't a knock through.
- No.
Doctor. it's bigger on the inside
than it is on the outside.
Hey. hey! We got there.
How is that possible?
How do you do that?
Well first. you have to imagine a very
big box fitting inside a very small box.
- Okay.
- Then. you have to make one.
It's the second part
people normally get stuck on.
Can we shut up. please.
Busy. busy.
I need to know if there's any interest
in what's inside this vault.
Why? What's inside it?
Something I don't want anyone
being too curious about.
So you put it
in the middle of a university?
Oh. valid point. Yeah. Nice.
Either the creature came here
specifically for what's in here
or it's just a coincidence.
- Just a coincidence.
- Well. we can't know that for sure.
Yeah. we can.
It was here for ages
before it did anything.
If it had work to do.
why would it lie around in a puddle?
I don't know. Maybe it's a student.
Oh. Banter. It's good. this.
Your go again.
Nardole...
We need to move away from the doors
and towards the TARDIS.
What if it attacks us?
Well that's good news.
It means it's not interested
in what's inside the vault.
it just wants to kill us.
Oh.
Run!
It's not interested in the vault.
It's chasing us.
Let's give it a proper challenge.
Let's see how far she's prepared to go.
What about my friend?
What about Heather? Can you save her?
First things first.
Let's see if we can survive her.
- But...
- Yes.
- We've moved again.
- We have.
- It was night...
- Yep.
Now it's day.
Definitely day.
- My God. We travelled in time?
- No. of course not.
We've travelled to Australia!
- How are you doing?
- How do you think?
Right. Um...
How do I help?
- Can I ask you a personal question?
- No.
- Can I anyway?
- Yes.
- Are you from space?
- No. of course not.
Nobody's from space.
I'm from a planet like everybody else.
This planet?
No. not specifically this one.
Doesn't make sense then.
- What doesn't?
- TARDIS.
If you're from another planet.
why would you name your box in English?
Those initials wouldn't work
in any other language!
- People don't generally bring that up.
- It looks a phone box.
Yes. Well. that's the cloaking device.
It sort of hides itself.
It's hidden itself as box
with "Pull to enter" on the front.
Uh-huh. it's stuck. It's supposed
to blend in but it's broken.
Doctor...
Out! Out! Everybody out! Shark attack.
- Where are we going?
- As far as we can.
She made Australia in a minute.
Let's see what she can really do.
Sir. we're leaving Earth.
What about the vault?
Oh. we're fine. If there's any trouble.
I'll get a message on this.
Let's see how long
it takes her to get here.
Where are we?
Other end of the universe.
23 million years in the future.
Oh yes. it's a time machine. too.
So. this is somewhere else.
This is a different planet.
Not Earth. a different one.
That's the general idea.
That's different sky.
Is it made of something different?
What is sky made of?
- Lemon drops.
- Really?
No. But wouldn't that be nice.
You can be very silly sometimes.
Do you know that?
So. how do we know
this water thing is actually dangerous?
- Because most things are.
- Hmm. That's true.
- Why? Is everything out here evil?
- Hardly anything is evil.
But most things are hungry.
Hunger looks very like evil
from the wrong end of the cutlery.
Or do you think that
your bacon sandwich loves you back?
So what is it?
And what was it doing on Earth?
Well. there were scorch marks
on the concrete where we found it.
could have been left by a shuttle craft.
The puddle. what did it look like?
I mean. if that was a car
what would you say that was?
An oil leak?
So it's space engine oil.
Intelligent oil.
Super intelligent space oil.
No! Part of the ship itself.
Shape-shifting fluid
that becomes anything it needs to be.
Oh. seriously?
But it spent ages laying
around being a puddle. What changed?
Your friend. She looked into it.
didn't she? More than once.
So?
Maybe it saw something it needed.
What was she like. your friend?
What did she want? What did she need.
Everywhere I go. I just wanna leave.
I think she wanted to leave.
See.
The puddle found a passenger.
A left-behind droplet of a liquid
spaceship. Single tear drop.
Alone in a strange world.
Then. one day it finds someone
who wants to fly away.
Not just the passenger...
More than a passenger.
It found a pilot so it ate her!
So. why is it chasing this one?
- Everything wants. everything needs.
- But why does it want her?
I don't know.
I don't know everything. Nardole.
I don't have it all written down.
You act like you do.
I act like I do because I don't.
It must be looking
for something.
Of course it is. Everything is.
But what?
What. in the end.
are any of us looking for?
We're looking for someone
who's looking for us.
Hey! Still making eyes at a puddle?
Bill!
Bill.
Back to the TARDIS.
Okay. It's fast. it time travels
and never gives up.
Plan!
Basic sterilization.
We're going to run that thing through
the deadliest fire in the universe.
Yes! That sounds excellent.
"The deadliest fire in the universe."
That's definitely good.
- How do we do that?
- The only way we can.
- we run through it first.
- Less good now.
No. not there. I don't like it there!
- Nardole!
- I don't like there.
I want you running interference.
can you do that?
- Can I say no. sir?
- No!
- Yes. then.
- Thank you.
But no. really.
Where are we?
Well. we're basically
in the middle of a war.
No. but... It's a war zone.
And this is just your basic skirmish.
And it's not as bad as it sounds.
I promise you.
Come on. I've got friends here.
Old friends.
I say friends...
The Doctor is detected.
Seek. Locate. Destroy.
- Are we still in the future?
- No. This is the past.
Doesn't look like the past.
- Are we safe here?
- Well. that's up to Nardole.
So probably not.
Oh.
Oh... Oh!
Keep moving. Doctor.
- Where are going?
- Into the fire. Come on.
Move! Move! Move!
Who are those guys?
Never mind them.
It's who they're firing at.
Come on.
What's that?
The deadliest fire
in the universe.
Identify. intruder. Identify.
Scan this device and identify me.
You are the Doctor.
You are an enemy of the Daleks!
Oh. yes I am.
Exterminate!
Exterminate.
- What was that thing?
- A Dalek.
- A what?
What's a Dalek?
Never mind. It's a Dalek.
Exterminate!
Exterminate...
That's wrong.
I know my Daleks and that's wrong.
Oh. I see.
You see what?
I've sealed the area.
All the Daleks are quarantined.
Except that one!
It's okay. this isn't a Dalek. Look.
Look at the eye.
Heather.
- Heather.
- Interesting.
You had a gun but you didn't use it.
Why?
You've already taken one person
from Earth.
I'm gonna let that pass because I have
to. but I will not let you take another.
Go.
Just go now. Fly away.
Why won't you just go?
- Promise you won't go.
- Promise.
Oh. my God.
I understand.
You what?
The last thing she said to me.
She promised she wouldn't
leave without me.
Her last conscious thought.
driving her across the universe.
- Never underestimate a crush.
- You don't have to tell me.
- What do we do?
- I don't know.
She's not chasing you.
she's inviting you.
Release her.
Release her from her promise.
You have to let me go.
I will.
I really liked you.
Bill.
Don't! Don't!
Don't do that. Listen.
Please. just listen to him.
Don't! Don't! Bill. let go!
Bill. listen to me.
Wha te ver she's showing you.
wha te ver she's letting you see.
it's a lure.
It's a trap.
She's making you part of her.
and you can never come back.
I see what you see.
It's beautiful.
Bill. let go! You have to let go!
She is not human any more.
Goodbye. Heather.
Good bye. Bill.
Whoa!
Bill. Bill!
Are you all right?
Yeah. I think so.
You don't look all right.
She's fine.
That's the Doctor for you.
Never notices the tears.
I don't think they're mine.
The vault alarm went off.
but it was nothing.
A student was sick outside and it
registered as a biological attack.
I saw it all for a moment.
Everything out there.
She was going to let me fly with her.
she was inviting me.
- But I was too scared.
- Scared is good.
Scared is rational.
She wasn't human any more.
Will we see her again?
Don't see how.
No. no. no. no. no.
You have to forget about that.
I don't see how I can.
I do.
Come here. Bill.
What's up?
- I just want to fix something...
- Whoa! What are you doing?
- Don't worry. this won't hurt at all.
- No. but tell me.
Nothing.
Yeah. Because I think
you were going to wipe my memory.
I'm not stupid. you know.
What's the trouble with you?
You don't think
anyone's ever seen a movie?
I know what a mind-wipe looks like.
I have no choice. I'm here for a reason.
I am in disguise.
I have promises to keep.
No one can know about me.
This is the most exciting thing
that's ever happened to me in my life.
- The only exciting thing.
- I'm sorry.
Okay.
Let me remember just for a week.
Just a week.
Okay. Well. just for tonight.
Just one night.
Come on. let me have
some good dreams for once.
Okay-
Do what you got to do.
But imagine...
just imagine how it would feel
if someone did this to you.
Get out.
- What?
- You can keep your memories.
Now get out before I change my mind.
Don't speak. Don't start.
Just run. Now. Go!
Shut up.
You shut up as well.
Will you all please just leave me alone.
I can't do that any more. I promised.
It's a big universe...
But maybe one day we'll find her.
What changed your mind?
Time.
Time?
And Relative Dimension in Space.
It means...
What the hell.
This is one
of the Earth's first colonies.
- What are they. alien birds?
- Tiny robots.
That is a robot.
He speaks emoji.
Where are all the people?
Ah!
What. you're going back in?
I'm having this really
childish impulse to blow it up.
- You're the one who should be afraid.
- Never.
Get ready.
I'm the Doctor.
I've been standing by the gates
of your world. keeping you all safe.
I'm not stopping now.
Any questions?